Sebastian Civarolo

281.635.5633 scivarolo@gmail.com sebastiancivarolo.com github.com/scivarolo

About

I am a full-stack software developer with five years of experience that enjoys exploring new technologies and finding new ways to solve problems. From my past life as a designer, I bring creative problem solving, a meticulous attention to detail, and a passion for building rich user experiences.

Education

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Full Stack Software Development, Javascript, Python OCT 2018-APR 2019

UNIVERSITY OF HOUSTON

BFA Graphic Communications 2007–2011

Technology

C#/.NET
Javascript
Typescript
React
SQL
Entity Framework
Azure DevOps
Azure Functions
Python
Webpack
Vite

Experience

APPLICATION DEVELOPER TEAM LEAD AUGUST 2022-PRESENT

PRIME Health Services, Franklin, TN

I currently lead the development team that maintains a bill review application and its supporting services. As a mentor, I prioritize pair programming regularly with the developers on my team to teach them new programming concepts, improve their problem-solving skills, and work on their ability to diagnose and troubleshoot issues.

- Work closely with stakeholders and the compliance and implementation teams to gather requirements for new features and ensure user needs are being met.
- Built an accounting system as part of the bill review platform that calculates fees for the review and pricing services applied to medical bills and generates PDF invoices.
- Architected a process for running background jobs utilizing queue-triggered Azure Functions with real-time progress updates in the UI.

APPLICATION DEVELOPER APRIL 2019-AUGUST 2022

PRIME Health Services, Franklin, TN

- Pushed for the modernization of the company's frontend applications—advocated for the use of React and Typescript to enable rich user experiences with complex interactions, while improving the developer experience and maintainability of the source code. Put in place the tooling for compiling/publishing these React applications using Webpack and Vite.
- Created a library of React components, hooks and helper functions that became the
 basis for all new UI development and enabled a consistent user experience across all
 applications. The library has a documentation site built with Storybook and includes a
 suite of unit tests using Jest with React Testing Library.
- Rebuilt two client-facing applications from the ground up as React-based single page applications powered by .NET backends: a client portal and a flagship bill review platform that processes thousands of medical bills monthly.
- Implemented a strategy for writing reliable repository unit tests utilizing a SQL database running in a Docker container with pre-defined seed data that can be reset between test runs. This also enabled isolated development on a local machine, preventing disruptions to the development database used by other team members.

GRAPHIC DESIGNER + WEB DEVELOPER 2011–2018

CORE Design Studio, Houston, TX

- Website planning, design, and development for non-profits and small businesses. Selftaught PHP, HTML, SCSS, and Javascript to deliver over 15 custom Wordpress sites.
- Concept planning, design, production of physical and interactive exhibits for museums, including touchscreen interactives built with Javascript for an educational water museum.
- Branding/Identity design, event collateral, magazines, art books, posters, signage systems and environmental graphic design with a strong emphasis on typography and meticulous attention to detail.